ultimateears.com 2012-06-16

# YOUR PRIVACY & SECURITY

#### YOUR PRIVACY & SECURITY

As your privacy is important to us, Logitech has prepared this Statement of Privacy and Security (“Statement”) so that you may better understand how Logitech uses and protects your personal information. Please take the time to review this page and contact us at [privacy@logitech.com](mailto:privacy@logitech.com) with any questions or concerns. 

COLLECTION OF INFORMATION  
HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION   
CONTROL & REVIEW OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION  
SAFE HARBOR   
PROTECTION OF INFORMATION  
CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT  

COLLECTION OF INFORMATION 

_Personal Information_

Logitech may ask you to register and provide personal information, such as when you purchase products from our online store, download software, register new products, access product information, features or programs, enter a contest or sweepstakes, or sign into a page that requires authorization. Logitech may also collect credit card information to bill you for products and services that you purchased. 

This personal information may include your name, e-mail address, user ID, domain name, URL, mailing address, and telephone number. Logitech may also collect demographic information such as your age, gender, zip code/postal code, education level, household income, operating system, preferences, interests, favorites, and whether you are a personal or business user. If you choose not to register and provide this information, you can still use most of Logitech’s Web site. Unfortunately, you will not be able to access areas that require registration. 

In addition, when you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will be asking for your friend’s name and e-mail address. Logitech will automatically send your friend a one-time e-mail inviting him or her to visit the site. Logitech does not store this information and only uses it for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail. 

_Children's Personal Information_

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from users under the age of 13. If we are made aware that we have such personal information, we will take reasonable steps to delete that information. 

_System Configuration Information_

Logitech automatically collects on our server logs certain information about your computer hardware and software when you visit our Web site or use Logitech’s online services, such as Logitech Desktop Messenger. This information may include such things as your IP address, cookie information, globally unique identifier, system, operating system, a description of any Logitech products connected and how such products are used, browser type, domain names, access times, service provider and referring Web site addresses. 

_Web Site Usage Information_

Logitech and its third party service providers track non-personally identifiable information about how you use our website through cookies, globally unique identifiers, Internet tags or web beacons in the aggregate, and track navigational data (log files, server logs, click stream). These allow us to track how you interact with Logitech online, and, with your permission, we can tie this information to your personal information to help us tailor communication to you. We also collect information such as the URL of the Web site you previously visited, and when you use our Web site. Logitech also keeps track of the pages you visit within our Web site and any transaction details (downloads, orders, requests, or referrals). You can set your browser to notify you when a cookie is sent or to refuse or delete cookies altogether, but certain features of our Web site might not work.

_Information for Using Harmony Remote Controls:_

If you use a Harmony Remote control or if you visit [www.harmonyremote.com](http://www.harmonyremote.com/) , Logitech may also collect certain information about your consumer electronic devices and/or TV channel configurations in order to help you program your remote control. 

_Information for Using SqueezeNetwork:_

If you use SqueezeNetwork to obtain Internet music streams, RSS, news feeds and podcasts or if you visit [www.squeezenetwork.com](http://www.squeezenetwork.com/), Logitech collects your player’s IP and MAC addresses, e-mail address, zip/postal code, and your user names and passwords in order to help you connect to third party Internet radio or music services for your Squeezebox or Transporter players. 

_Personal Information_

With your express permission, Logitech collects, integrates, and uses your personal information to help enhance and personalize your use of our Web site, products and services. This will enable the following: (1) you to quickly find software, services or information on [www.logitech.com](http://www.logitech.com/), (2) Logitech to create Web site content and other services most relevant or customized to you, (3) for you to be alerted about product and Web site upgrades and updates, special offers, promotions, newsletters, latest product announcements, upcoming events, programs and other new services from Logitech; and (4) to invite you to participate in product and service surveys or programs. Logitech uses this information to communicate with you either via the Internet, e-mail, mail or telephone only after you give your express permission for such communication. (The only exception to this Statement are “service e-mails” that may notify you about system downtimes, product problems or recalls, password reminder e-mails, etc.) 

We also use anonymous and aggregated data to create statistics and reports for various business purposes. We may aggregate anonymous data and share the anonymous data with our co-marketing partners in order to offer all our customers potentially desirable products and services as well as to improve our content and services. 

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support, processing transactions or performing statistical analysis of our services. We will only provide those companies the personal information (such as e-mail address) that they need to deliver the service. Our service providers are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. 

From time to time we supplement the information we collect from the site with information from offline or third party sources. We use this information to enhance or overlay the “profile” of customers and business contact information. This supplementary data is therefore tied to corporate contact information and in some cases personally identifiable information. We also may internally compare lists collected from our other sites or within our family of companies to remove duplicate entries. 

_E-Mail Messaging_

Logitech will periodically send our registered users e-mail messages about our products and services. When sending you e-mail, we may use an image called a single pixel GIF that allows us to format messages tailored to your computer’s capabilities. We also use this technology to determine, in the aggregate, how many people open our e-mails. When you initiate a response by clicking on a link within an e-mail, you are redirected onto the Internet. We then record your individual response to help us deliver information that is more relevant to your interests. 

_Disclosure of Information_

Logitech keeps your personally identifiable information confidential. We do not disclose it to third parties or others that do not have a need to know such information except under certain circumstances. Set forth below are additional circumstances where Logitech may share your personal information: 

* Certain of our employees, independent contractors and service providers may have access to your personally identifiable information necessary for the sole purpose of helping us run our business. These employees and contractors have confidentiality and security obligations. 
* Our affiliates, subsidiaries and third party service providers as we deem appropriate. 
* We may disclose your personally identifiable information to another business entity should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity; or to any organization involved in a merger, transfer, or sale of our assets or business. 
* Before we disclose your personally identifiable data for other reasons, we will first obtain your consent, for example via e-mail, click-through, an online opportunity to opt-out, or otherwise. 
* If you post any information in public areas of our Web site, such as chat rooms and message boards, it will be available to the public and we may reuse and republish such information at our discretion and in accordance with our Terms of Use. 
* To protect and defend the rights or property of Logitech, including its Web sites. 
* We may also share your personally identifiable information to respond to law enforcement requests, court orders or other legal processes or if we believe that such disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent or respond to illegal activities, fraud, physical threats to you or others, national security threats or as otherwise required by any applicable law or regulation. 

In the event that we disclose your personally identifiable information as set out above, we will require third party organizations that have access to your personally identifiable information to protect and maintain your personally identifiable information in compliance with the terms and conditions of this Statement. 

_Prohibited Disclosures_

Except as set forth above, Logitech will not disclose your personally identifiable information to any third party, including advertisers, without your explicit consent. In addition, Logitech will not share, trade, rent, or otherwise disclose your personal information, Logitech’s e-mail list or address list to third parties for their promotional purposes. 

Back to top

CONTROL & REVIEW OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION 

When you register, Logitech offers choices for the collection, use and sharing of personal information. In addition, you may also stop the delivery of future communications including newsletters, special offers and updates from Logitech by unsubscribing at any time. For instance, each email you receive contains instructions explaining how to stop receiving such e-mails. You may also contact us using any of the vehicles listed below to opt-out.

Phone: +1 510-795-8500  
Email: [privacy@logitech.com](mailto:privacy@logitech.com)   
Postal Mail: Logitech Privacy Officer, 6505 Kaiser Drive, Fremont, CA 94555 USA 

Web site: <http://www.logitech.com/subscribe>

If your personal information changes (such as zip/postal code, phone, or e-mail or postal address), or if you no longer desire our products or services, we provide a way for you to change or delete/deactivate it. This can be done by visiting the subscription management page on our Web site or by e-mailing us at [privacy@logitech.com](mailto:privacy@logitech.com). Logitech will respond to your request to review the information we have on file for you within 30 days from receiving such request. 

We provide you the opportunity to “opt-out” of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product and/or service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form. 

Back to top

SAFE HARBOR 

Personal information collected on this site may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Logitech or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities. By using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. Logitech complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. For more information about Safe Harbor, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Safe Harbor Web site regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. 

PROTECTION OF INFORMATION 

Logitech is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access. These systems are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

Logitech, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This Statement covers the site www.logitech.com. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to our users´ privacy, we have agreed to disclose our privacy practices and have them reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Statement, you should first contact us at [privacy@logitech.com](mailto:privacy@logitech.com) with any questions or concerns. All customer complaints will be formally reviewed by Logitech. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php> in the United States. TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with Logitech to resolve your concerns. Please understand, however, that the TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site ([www.logitech.com](http://www.logitech.com/)) and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the site. 

Back to top

CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT 

Logitech will occasionally update this Statement. When Logitech posts changes to this Statement, you will see the word "updated" next to the Statement link on the front page of [www.logitech.com](http://www.logitech.com/). If there are material changes to this Statement or in how Logitech will use your personal information, Logitech will prominently post such changes prior to implementing the change. In any case we will not make any changes that are less protective of your personal information collected in the past without your consent. 

Logitech encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Logitech is protecting your information. 

Thank you for your interest in Logitech and our products.  
Logitech Privacy Officer   
Logitech Inc.  
6505 Kaiser Drive  
Fremont, California 94555 USA  

Revised September 9, 2009
